A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers' Files, Financial Files FA1835
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers' Files, Financial Files
1975-1986
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council
FA1835
1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document containers
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains accounting office records related to fellowships and grants, including acceptance letters, budgets, and payment schedules, for fellowships awarded by SSRC committees. Each folder typically contains a summary table listing award recipients for a particular year. Both predoctoral grants and postdoctoral research grants are represented throughout the collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2017 by the SSRC and ingested by RAC as Accession 2017:018.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in one series: Accounting Office Fellowship Files, 1975-1986
- Accounting Office Fellowship Files, 1975-1986; 1; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
  - SSRC-Fulbright Research Grants, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Law Training Fellowship Program of the Subcommittee on Law and Social Structure of the Joint Committee on the Near and Middle East, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Committee on Indochina Studies of the Committee on Southeast Asia, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Latin America Predoctoral Fellowship Program April 1978 Grant List, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subcommittee on Monetary Research, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Subcommittee on Economic/Monetary Research, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subcommittee on Monetary Research, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Ad-hoc Committee on Inter-area Research Postdoctoral Research Grants, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Research Training Fellowships, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Grants for Advanced Research, Predoctoral Research - Latin America and the Caribbean, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13-16)
  - Joint Committee on Latin American Studies, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18-23)
  - Joint Committee on Korean Studies, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 24-28)
  - Joint Committee on Japanese Studies, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Joint Committee on South Asia, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30-35)
  - Joint Committee on Southeast Asia, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 36-40)
  - Joint Committee on South Asia, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Joint Committee on Near and Middle East, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 42-44)
  - Joint Committee on Contemporary China, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 45-48)
  - China and Inner Asia Fellowship Program, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Western Europe Fellowship Program, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 50-54)
  - Research Program for the Near and Middle East Research Grants, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 55-57)
  - Joint Committee on Latin American Studies, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - International Research Fellowship Program for Western Europe, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Grants for Advanced Research, Latin America and the Caribbean, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
  - International Research Fellowship Program for Africa, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 62-63)
  - Joint Committee on African Studies, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 64-67)
  - Latin America and Caribbean Fellowship Program, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 68-69)